[{"id":45,"question":"Which of the answers listed below refers to a package management system most often used on Debian and Debian-based Linux distributions?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"kde","answer_b":"apt","answer_c":"yum","answer_d":"rpm","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"true","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_b","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":702,"question":"Which command can be used to display basic information about your server?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"uname","answer_b":"info","answer_c":"ls","answer_d":"show","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":692,"question":"Which service runs on each Kubernetes node and ensures containers are running in a pod?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"etcd","answer_b":"kubelet","answer_c":"scheduler","answer_d":"kubeadm","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"true","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":"The kubelet is the primary \u201cnode agent\u201d that runs on each node. It can register the node with the apiserver using one of: the hostname; a flag to override the hostname; or specific logic for a cloud provider.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Kubernetes"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":670,"question":"Which is the invalid file name in UNIX?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"LINUX","answer_b":"a.widows","answer_c":"bill .gates","answer_d":"All of the above","answer_e":"None of the above","answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"true","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":713,"question":"Which command can be used to stop the current executing process in the background?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"kill","answer_b":"stop","answer_c":"remove","answer_d":"rm","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"},{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":681,"question":"Who designed the Linux OS?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"Linus Torvalds","answer_b":"Steve Jobs","answer_c":"Steve Wozniak","answer_d":"Steve Linus","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":647,"question":"Which command can be used to count characters in a text file?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"ccount","answer_b":"fsize","answer_c":"count","answer_d":"wc","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"true","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":652,"question":"What is the She-bang line in a shell script","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"#","answer_b":"#!","answer_c":"!#","answer_d":"None of the above","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"true","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":737,"question":"How to delete a pod in Kubernetes using the type and name specified in pod.json?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"kubectl delete .\/pod.json","answer_b":"kubectl delete -f .\/pod.json","answer_c":"kubectl remove -f .\/pod.json","answer_d":"kubectl remove .\/pod.json","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"true","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Kubernetes"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":705,"question":"Deployment Controllers are part of","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"Master Controller Manager","answer_b":"kube-scheduler","answer_c":"etcd manager","answer_d":"API Controller Manager","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":"A Deployment provides declarative updates for Pods and ReplicaSets.You describe a desired state in a Deployment, and the Deployment Controller changes the actual state to the desired state at a controlled rate. You can define Deployments to create new ReplicaSets, or to remove existing Deployments and adopt all their resources with new Deployments.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Kubernetes"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":47,"question":"What is the name of a Linux utility used for managing software packages on Red Hat and Red Hat-based Linux distributions?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"yum","answer_b":"apt","answer_c":"apt-get","answer_d":"grub","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":685,"question":"What is UMASK?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"UMASK is a Unix environment variable, which automatically sets file permissions created files.","answer_b":"UMASK is a Unix environment variable, which automatically sets the file visibility.","answer_c":"UMASK is a Unix environment variable, which not really used anymore and is considered legacy.","answer_d":"UMASK is a Unix environment variable, which is replaced by the chmod command now however it's still largely used.","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"},{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":662,"question":"Which command can give first found difference between two file after comparing?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"diff","answer_b":"cmp","answer_c":"Common","answer_d":"stat","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"true","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":691,"question":"Which operator can be used to throw a process into background?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"&","answer_b":"&&","answer_c":"|","answer_d":"||","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":1071,"question":"From which file does the command `free` takes it's information","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"\/proc\/meminfo","answer_b":"\/proc\/freemem","answer_c":"\/proc\/memfree","answer_d":"\/dev\/meminfo","answer_e":"\/dev\/freemem","answer_f":"\/dev\/memfree"},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":680,"question":"How can you display the top 10 number of lines of a file?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"head \u2212n 10 file.txt","answer_b":"head -f 10 file.txt","answer_c":"head --display-only 10 file.txt","answer_d":"head -show 10 file.txt","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"},{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":745,"question":"How to show the metrics for a given node in Kubernetes?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"kubectl ps node my-node","answer_b":"kubectl resources node my-node","answer_c":"kubectl top node my-node","answer_d":"kubectl uptime node my-node","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"true","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Kubernetes"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":21,"question":"Which of the following is a text editor that can be used in command mode to edit files on a Linux system?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"vi or vim","answer_b":"lsof","answer_c":"open","answer_d":"edit","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":16,"question":"Which command is used to create new directory?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"dir","answer_b":"newdir","answer_c":"mkdir","answer_d":"cdir","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"true","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_c","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":223,"question":"Which keyword is used with the UPDATE command to change the value?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"CHANGE","answer_b":"MODIFY","answer_c":"ADD","answer_d":"SET","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"true","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"MySQL"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"}]